The Breakfast is a drama, comedy film directed by Peter Sheridan.
Curly Mulligan is the pupil who brings the
headmaster a full fry-up every morning.
When the head finds a hair in his breakfast, all hell breaks loose.
Curly Mulligan, played by Gavin Dowdall.
Brother Ledwidge, played by Frank McDonald.
Smiley Byrne, played by Patrick Hyland.
Skinny Palmer, played by Kevin James.
Boy Buttering Bread, played by Gerard Cannon.
Boy Cutting Bread, played by Peter Rogers.
Breakfast on Pluto is a 2005 comedy-drama film directed by Neil Jordan from a screenplay he
co-wrote with Patrick McCabe, based on McCabe's 1998 novel of the same name.
Set during the Troubles in the 1970s, the film stars Cillian Murphy as a transgender woman
foundling who leaves her small Irish town for London in search of her long-lost mother.
Stephen Rea, Brendan Gleeson and Liam Neeson also star.
The film explores themes of boarding school, breakfast,
dark comedy, brotherhood, young boy.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.